NIVENDHA KANNAN

SOFTWARE PROD AND PLAT ENG TEAM LEAD, 8.5 YEARS

TECHNOLOGIES

ReactJS, Next Js, NodeJS, GraphQI, Webpack, HTML5, CSS3

EDUCATION

Madras institute of technology, Bachelors in Electronics Instrumentation, 2014

CONTACT

Web:<u>nivendha.me</u>
Blog: <u>blog.nivendha.me</u>
Mail:<u>knivendha@gmail.com</u>
github:<u>https://github.com/nivendha</u>

stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/4211588/nivendha

Mobile: 9790717916

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nivendha/

Github works

deno.land

Deno is a TS and Rust based runtime environment built over Rust-v8 and Tokio (event loop implementation)
Currently working on beginner level issues and doc fix PR

SUMMARY

I am a skilled UI developer with strong experience in web application development. I have also worked as a full-stack developer and handled backend service integration while developing applications.

In addition, I have a good knowledge of various technologies such as ReactJS, graphQI, Typescript, and NodeJS.

EXPERIENCE

Accenture, Software Prod & Plat Eng Team Lead

July 2021 - Present, Bangalore, India

Working on building SAS application with react, next js, and Google cloud services

Imaginea Technologies Inc., Principal Engineer

July 2016 - July 2021, Bangalore, India

Worked on a web application for a client using ReactJS, Node, GraphQI, Express, and other technologies.

Intellect Design Arena, Developer

July 2014 - June 2016, Chennai, India

Developed an adaptive design MVC Framework using bootstrap's UI components , Templating was done Using handlebars as template engine

PROJECTS

Tamr

Tamr is a cloud-native data mastering solution (cloud MDM) that accelerates analytics through machine learning (ML), available on Google Cloud, Azure and AWS.

Thumbsignin

ThumbSignIn is a solution for passwordless authentication, it makes use of biometric authentication via fingerprint. It helps to overcome the pain of remembering the passwords and prevents the security attacks that are happening using passwords.

Flydubai

flydubai is a government-owned budget airline in Dubai. Worked on the UI plugins of a web portal for destination search, ticket booking and offers.

Quantiply

Quantiply provides a Data Science platform that helps organizations/data scientists spend less time worrying about infrastructure and more focusing on their business problems.

NIVENDHA **K**ANNAN

SOFTWARE PROD AND PLAT ENG TEAM LEAD, 8.5 YEARS

PROJECT DETAILS

TAMR	Role: worked in building a Saas user interface web application, did log collections system via node js and multiple POC- Monroepo via lerna, dataflow designer ui via reactflow, generic network manager with fetch, error handling and debugging Stack: ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Express Js, Webpack,
THUMBSIGNIN	Role: Revamped the project in building dashboards and pluggable widget functionalities to the existing product. Brought in server-side rendering for fast web performance, used graphQl for data manipulation and dockerized the entire app. Worked on redesigning the entire static page UI in a short period of time.
	Customised the 'storybook' into a sandbox environment, for thumbsignin react components to be built into js widgets. These can be plugged into any web app independent of the framework used. Stack: ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Express Js, Webpack, GraphQL, Docker, react-md, HTML5, SASS
FLY DUBAI	Role: Worked as a javascript developer in building Web components with an object-oriented approach, the UI is built as a mobile-first, adaptive design with bootstrap and jquery library Stack: Bootstrap, jquery, HTML, CSS
OHANITIDI V	The Webapp was built to have support for modularised UI components that can be integrated independently of the javascript framework that gets used. Role: Worked as a UI developer. Responsible for developing data visualisation components
QUANTIPLY	built using D3 and Highcharts, Built custom components for data processing and Live data streaming in Node-red. Stack: node-red, Node JS, Express, HTML5, CSS3